<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title>Bo Jeanes - personal</title>
	<link href="https://bjeanes.com/tags/personal/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://bjeanes.com"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2022-11-26T00:22:42+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://bjeanes.com/tags/personal/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Happier as a Hacker</title>
		<published>2012-09-06T00:22:42+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-11-26T00:22:42+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://bjeanes.com/posts/happier-as-a-hacker/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://bjeanes.com/posts/happier-as-a-hacker/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve grown a lot in the last few years, personally and, specifically, in my career. My values have changed and it’s
affected the way I think and work.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There has been a gradual progression towards caring more and more about the Right Way™ to do things. For example, more
than ever before, I value simplicity and clarity over ease and cleverness (an epidemic that greatly afflicts the Ruby
community, in my opinion).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, these values have come at a cost to me. Somewhere along the way, I complacently let &lt;em&gt;getting it right&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; become far
more important than &lt;em&gt;getting it done&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.” Don’t get me wrong, getting things right is very important — where I went wrong
was valuing getting it right the &lt;strong&gt;first&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may not plague others to the extent that it has me, but this misplaced obsession has gotten in the way of progress.
It’s caused a type of analysis paralysis not unlike writers’ block; I discard ideas and directions too early because
they aren’t “good enough.” But exploring a potentially bad direction is still being better than having no direction
— which is the only place you end up when you discard ideas before they have a chance to blossom.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the eternal words of &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Into_the_Woods&quot;&gt;Little Red Ridinghood&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isn&#x27;t it nice to know a lot?
And a little bit not.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was happier as a hacker, blissfully ignorant as I was, because I got things done.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s time to become a hacker again; it’s time to be creative and explorative, and work towards &lt;em&gt;approximating&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; the Right
Way™, iteratively. Truly, this is one of the great realizations of Agile — focus on progress instead of planning and
pre-empting every possible outcome.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can’t forget that.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Narrator&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: He forgot that. [ed: 2022]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
